Loot hello everyone Shyam hair and welcome back to the
channel so as I had
promised you last year that I will
take ICICI Bank so today I have brought it and
we will discuss all the student related points history subject functions on this channel
before that subscribe to the channel you will
definitely get notification if you
like the video please like share and you
can comment I had an interview of a
bank in Mumbai
where is its corporate office list office
in Baroda Gujarat what is its
type which bank is it private sector
bank and Indian Banking and Financial
Services Company its total how many rupees
from where 5050 this is done
that subsidy now we will see what is
ICICI Prudential Life Insurance
ICICI Lombard ICICI
Prudential ICICI Securities
MD & CEO and Chairman Girish Chaturvedi so
now we will see the complete explanation
what is the full form of ICICI Bank
full form of ICICI IS means
Industrial C means Credit I means
Investment Industrial  Credit and
Investment Corporation of India Bank
in the form of Bank of India and Indian Indian Representative of Development
which Indian Business School and Medium
Project Subscribe Like
and on such primary family courts
loot when in 1919 LPG NPTEL you must
know help ji means reaction
liberalization and globalization ok and
privatization and liberalization
privatization and globalization so
definitely subscribe notice and wanted to emerge as a development
financial institution
which was a diversified fund
Subscribe Like and along with
subscribe other companies had
other products and services because changes were taking place to
change
privatization and globalization had started coming
so it also diverted its working a bit so to
match the changing modern economy of India globally
ICICI started providing many products and services to its friends
so this was the history of
ICICI Bank ICICI Bank PIN was set in
1994 it was set to 99 that
when in 1994 it was set as a bank
These operations were carried out because the scenario
was changing, okay, the economy of India was becoming a thing,
after liberalization came, so
in 1994, as a part of a group in corporate,
ICICI became the first Indian company to get itself
listed on the New York Stock Exchange, and it belonged to an
Asian country, so it became, that is, it
joined New York.
ICICI became the first Indian company and was taken
on notice of the New York Stock Exchange as a commercial bank,
which would do public demand deposit assets,
public deposit assets related work,
and other services it would provide to the customers.
For this,
ICICI Bank was merged so that the
value of ICICI could participate in this disgusting global market.
Okay, so in October 2018, the
Board of Directors and ICICI
Bank, ICICI and its two other retail pack
abs, that is, the first and the
October 2018 listing of ICICI Bank was waived,
which was named Personal
Financial Services Limited.  The second
Capital Services Limited was done, both were made ICICI
Bank, which got strengthened
and got Jan22, so this is the complete
history background, you have come to know
which companies are included in the Times Group company,
let us see ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance Company, ICICI
Securities, ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company, ICICI Prudential AMC, ... Securities, ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company, ICICI Securities, ICICI Securities, ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company, ICICI Securities, ICICI Securities, ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company, ICICI Securities, ICICI Securities, ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company, ICICI Securities, ICICI Securities, ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company, ICICI Pru
Been Shri Ram,
Mr. Uday Vichitra, take all these directors,
so this is the point, this should be the
problem of the shareholders, this should be created, the
appointment should be as per Regulation 90
and should be, independent
directors were appointed for appointment,
well according to the Active Companies Act, they will not be responsible for retirement
during rotation according to the President of China, so
these three conditions will be the terms of appointment,
so independent directors from there,
mostly from the committees, which come here from the committee, so let's
see, director
of independent director committee, committee, committee
and social responsibility committee, committee,
customer service committee, monitoring
committee, information technology committee, committee
and review committee for identification
of default
and not cooperative words, so this
department, wherever these committees are, wherever they are, from
here the majority of
independent directors product,
ICICI provides its senior citizens
can edit as many people as deposit
important some points information
branches, where where, where where, South
Africa and Singapore, Hong Kong and Bahrain and
representative offices, where where,
Bangladesh,
Malaysia  Indonesia, its
representative here, you mean, he was present here at not present
time, first Indian
President, first Indian private bank, the
largest private sector bank and
subscribe, first commercial bank,
ICICI, chief
scientist, from an
important point of view, let us now look at the
objective question development and which is
related to the public, that is, which develops commercial
enterprise edition and
leads subscribe enterprises, it promotes
private donors, industrial
investment, private partnership,
industrial investment and does
this tweet
question of industrial units in the market, to
rebuild the industrial unit, to
illuminate its jobs that have realized, it provides funds, okay
let's do the function strictly that ICC chief
provides for long term debt and
equity and equity and provides for this, it provides for the
appointment of shares, it
provides for other private investment, that
for railways, provident fund company itself will have to
invest,
religious, such comments policy,
what will be played in provident fund, which will
again, now we will have to do relative study
and how will we have to do adventure exploration
Along with this, there are
some special polish related issues of the government and central government, it
adds to it, guides them,
tightens the skin for private
companies, so this function hangs, if you
look at it a little more, then
subscribe and it provides industrial
security,
if it is within 15 years, then
it provides the
requirement of coat and pants, it provides enough
technical services, friends,
what else does it do, it makes current payment for
those, to provide credit facility for
promoting industrial equipment and
payment, it provides credit facility
for purchasing or for taking
appointments, it provides financial
services, if it is related to financial services, if
you liked this dish then
please like and share, thank you for
watching, this is
loot
jhal